

Evgeniy Babiychuk

Javascript / React Native Developer

I am a web and mobile developer with 8 years of experience, specializing in React and React Native. Throughout my career, I have successfully created and enhanced numerous web and mobile apps, working across various industries including e-commerce, social media platforms, blockchain, data visualizations, and SaaS projects. I am always eager to explore new technologies and seek out fresh opportunities in this field. Before starting work on a project, I think ahead how it should be in the end, introducing myself as a consumer of the project. I excel at working collaboratively to solve complex problems and enjoy being part of a team.

Tel: +38(093)-589-50-84

e-mail: evgeniybabiychuk.dev01@gmail.com

Skills

-Web Development

 React.js, Gatsby, Next.JS, React(hooks), React-router-Redux, React-Thunk, React-Saga, Context, Styled Component, Apollo GraphQL, Storybook, Ant Design, Lottie

Vue: VueX, Vuetify, Vue Material, Nuxt

AngularJS, Angular V1, V4, V5, V6, V7

Node.JS/Express.JS

Ember.JS

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery, LESS/SASS, Ajax, Json, XML, Tailwind, Foundation

- SQL, MYSQL, MongoDB, Dynamo DB, PostgreSQL
- GIT/Docker/Apache/Nginx
- · AWS, Firebase, QuickBlox

-Mobile App Development

- Programming Language: Javascript, Typescript
- Frameworks & Libraries: React Native, Redux, Middlewares (Saga, Thunk, Persist etc.), Axios, NativeBase,
 React Native Elements, Lottie for RN
- DBMS: Realm, Firebase, SQLite, Async Storage, DynamoDB
- VCS: git, svn
- CI/CD: Jenkins, Fastlane, Gitlab CI
- Code Review : Cross-review
- Other/Integration: UI tests, Unit tests, Location tracking, REST API, GraphQL, Notification, Deep linking, Social networks integration, IAP
- IDE: Webstorm, Android studio, Xcode, VScode, Atom;
- Tools: node, yarn, expo, expo-kit, performance debugging

Career History

Front-End (React) Developer

"Merehead"

June 2020 - Aug 2021

Merehead is a outsourcing company, mainly focuses on developing fintech and blockchain solutions.

My Role:

- · Developing user-facing features using React.js.
 - -Setup applications from scratch.
 - -Building reusable components and front-end libraries for future use.
 - -Translating designs and wireframes into high quality code.
 - -Optimizing components for maximum performance across a vast array of web-capable devices and browsers.
 - -Deploying code to staging/production
- Participation in the development of 6 projects in the direction of marketplace, blockchain, social network project, and a small private site.

Work with: TypeScript, React(hooks), React-router, Redux, Redux-Thunk, Redux-Saga, Git, ESlint, WebSocket, RESTful APIs, Postman, React Hooks, Axios, Styled Components, Stripe, i18next

Front-End Developer

"Jerelia"

July 2019 - January 2020

Jerelia is the first Ukrainian network company producing products that will please all members of the family! **My Role**:

- Developed a new website https://jerelia.com/ with React/Redux, Material-UI, Axios, swager, ASP.net, REST API
- Create a module "landing constructor" https://babiychuk.github.io/landing-page-creator/.
 Built with react/redux, material-ui, json.

Front-End Developer

"Ukravtonomgaz"

June 2017 - March 2019

Ukravtonomgaz is a Ukrainian group operating in the liquefied gas market. Founded in 2009.

My Role:

- Created web service https://lpg-car.com/. The project was placed on a remote server in Ubuntu.
 I've worked with Linux, PostgreSQL, gulp, twig, less, flex, javascript, html5, css3, Git.
 Made adaptive webpages with API, google maps, jQuery slick-slider.
- Built support websites of the company https://ukravtonomgaz.ua/
- Developed a new website https://ukravtonomgaz.com.ua/. This project has been built on Drupal CMS.

Front-End Developer

"Energorynok"

September 2016 - June 2017

Energorynok is a state-owned company founded in 2000 established by the state in the person of the Cabinet of Ministers of Ukraine and is a Party to the Agreement between the members of the Wholesale Electricity Market of Ukraine.

My Role:

- Worked with Oracle Database, created data tables, triggers, sequences, wrote functions on php for received data from the Oracle DB and through API, jQuery, ajax and bootstrap in Front I created some calculators: http://www.nerc.gov.ua/?calc_gas http://www.nerc.gov.ua/?calc_nc
- Support website of the company http://www.er.gov.ua/
 Made some functions, modules, pages with javascript, html5, css3.
- Created landing pages and some functions with bootstrap, javaScript, ajax, chartJS https://www.oree.com.ua/ https://www.gpee.com.ua/
- Worked with Google maps API, iCheck, javaScript to show 4 types markers on Ukraine map, markers drew on Photoshop https://babiychuk.github.io/sites/energyPoints/eneggypoints.html

React Native Developer

"Reelfolio"

January 2020 - January 2021

Reelfolio is the online social networking platform for the filmmakers.

My Role:

- Developing mobile UI with react native framework
- Developing backend with node.JS
- · Integrate the api and unit test
- Deploying code to staging/production

React Native Developer

"Marine snow"

Feb 2021 - Feb 2022

Marine snow is the premier global hall of songs, curated and contextualized.

My Role:

- Mobile UI build of the Discovery part and onboarding logic implementation
- Create the music orbs by using the lottie json
- Optimize the codebase to reduce the memory and CPU usage
- Gamification of the music play logic
- Integrate backend api and unit test
- Deploying code to staging/production

React Native Developer

"Hipcamp"

April 2019 - January 2020 Travel Booking app

My Role:

- Filtering Function
- Social media integration
- Enhance Map service

Education

National Aviation University (Kiev, Ukraine)

Institute of Computer Information Technologies

from 2015 to 2017 - Software Engineering, full-time education (Master)

from 2012 to 2015 - Software Engineering (Bachelor)

College of Information Technology and Land Management

from 2008 to 2012 - Software development (Junior Specialist)